insurance policy covers hospitalizations
which are 24 hours or above it yes even
if your hospitalization is necessary and
contains an active treatment still by
definition it has to be 24 hours or
above it in order to cover that
particular hospitalization basically uh
the logic behind health insurance was to
cover the larger expenses right and
that's why this particular threshold so
what will happen if the hospitalization
is less than 24 hours see it's not a
strict rule but yes there is an
important exception called Day Care
hospitalization now the question will
come dayare hospitalization so simply
put with the advancement in medical
technology the treatments which were
happening earlier in more than 24 hours
are now being completed in less than a
day and such treatments are called
daycare hospitalization and these are
covered under your health insurance
policy so uh let's take few examples you
will uh you will get a better
understanding uh for example eyes the
cataract surgery it was taking earlier
more than 24 hours and now it is
happening in less than a day and it is a
daycare hospitalization and covered
under your health insurance policy
similarly uh cancer related uh
radiotherapy chemotherapy earlier more
than 24 hours right now it is happening
in less than 24 hours and is a daycare
hospitalization and is covered under
your health insurance policy a few more
uh let's say sinus surgery dialysis uh
or even tonsilectomy the surgery for
tonsils or surgery for tongue all these
things were taking more than 24 hours
and are now happening in less than 24
hours in less than a day and hence it's
a daycare hospitalization and is an
exception and covered in your health
insurance policy but wait there is one
important fine print which you must know
about this particular exception daycare
hospitalization so there are some
insurers which give a Lumar list of such
treatments or conditions they cover but
on the other hand there are some
insurance of liberal insurance which
give a comprehensive coverage to cover
all daycare treatments but yes it needs
to fall in the definition right so hope